The wind is pretty solid. How you doing?
Very good. Good to meet you. You're everywhere.
Yes sir, I appreciate that.
That's great.
Who am I here with today?
Patrick Bede.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
250 million.
This property we're on right now, the guy that
owned this bought it for 25 million in 2018.
This was announced that's going on
the public market for an auction.
4,400 people were interested in this property.
131 signed an NDA and then
there is the day that everybody's bidding.
You have to put a million
dollars to compete. Today the auction comes.
We ended up buying this for 25.2 million dollars cash.
We wired the money a
week later. We bought the property.
This is probably a 40, 50 million dollar property.
Having cash allows you to pick things up.
Unfortunately, not having cash when the market goes
bad, a lot of people don't make it.
They want to become Patrick Bede, wealthy in today's world.
They want to become really successful. Your last message.
Let's listen.
Guys, we're about to go fly
out to Miami, Florida to interview
multiple hundred million dollar entrepreneurs.
We're Patrick Bette David.
This is a guy who went from dead broke
as an immigrant to building and selling a company
for several hundred million dollars.
Guys, this interview that we're about to do
with Patrick is going to be a masterclass
on all things business from sales to negotiations to money.
You do not want to miss out on this.
So stay tuned from start to finish to figure
out how you can be just like Patrick and dominate
any industry that you're in.
Let's head out to Miami. Go meet Patrick.
Come on.
The wind is pretty solid.
I saw you.
Very good.
Good to meet you.
You're everywhere.
That's great.
And how old are you about 22?
Okay.
22 years old.
What you're doing is very important.
Specifically that you're 22 years old doing this.
Imagine how many billions of people have
watched your message, whether it's TikTok or Instagram.
Very important what you're doing.
You want to do it here with the wind.
You're not worried about the wind.
Yes.
You're good with that.
Yeah, no, we're good.
Everything.
Yeah.
Go for it.
Right over here.
Yeah.
How do we do step right over here?
Awesome.
Who am I here with today?
Patrick Bede.
And for those that don't know what industry
did you decide to pursue a career in?
First one was insurance.
Now it's media and consulting.
Yeah.
You built your wealth in insurance.
There's a saying that I love concentration builds wealth.
Diversification keeps it.
At what point should an entrepreneur begin to diversify?
I would put the number 10 billion plus.
When I first got in, I
read a book called Blue Ocean Strategy.
When we had an emergency meeting with 20,
30 of us, we got in and I said,
I want you to help us
find a blue ocean for the company.
At the time I was selling life insurance.
You're talking disability, stocks,
bonds, mutual funds, variable annuities.
I said, we're not doing all that.
We eliminated everything.
I'm serious.
766, 3126 life and health.
I use none of my licenses, but only life insurance.
We grew it from 66
agents to we've licensed 60,000 agents.
And eventually we sold the company.
Now you've consulted for some of
the biggest companies in the world.
In today's world, eight out of 10
companies don't make it past five years.
When you're consulting for a company,
what's the most common mistake, the number
one mistake you're seeing business owners make
that prevents them from scaling and having that longevity?
Well, the operator, everything rises
and falls on the operator.
The operator isn't maniacally focused in
growing the business and isn't emotionally stable.
He's going to have a hard time.
He's got to be maniacally focused.
He's got to be emotionally stable.
He's got to be able to understand who to
take feedback from and not to take feedback from.
Sometime when you're first getting started, you
may hire somebody with a Harvard degree,
but go, my God, this
guy's got a degree from Harvard.
He must know more than I do.
And you allow that person to take it.
You allow them to change the culture of the company.
And then you're like, wait a minute,
we just lost what we used to have.
Degrees don't mean anything.
First, they have to come in and prove to
you that they understand what the culture of the
company is all about.
And you have to have the wherewithal
to know I should take this feedback.
I shouldn't take this feedback.
And then meanwhile, drive for the vision.
Don't get distracted with the vision.
Guys, this interview with PBD has been amazing so far.
We're about to get right back to it.
But I've got a very, very
special announcement to make real quick.
So a couple of months ago, I launched
and created one of the largest entrepreneur communities
in the entire world.
The School of Mentors, where every single
week I host live calls with the millionaires
and the billionaires that I interview on this
channel, where the members inside of the community,
you guys that join have the ability to
ask your questions and speak directly to the millionaires
and the billionaires that I interview.
So you can get the necessary knowledge
that you need, where you can learn skills.
For example, some of the mentors I've had
on calls with people like Todd Napola, who
owns over $500 million worth of real estate.
And he taught our community how
to get access to capital and create
money for the business.
Wealth and real estate without a ton of money.
Or how about Sean Mike, who's done
over $3 billion in sales throughout his career.
He taught our community the art
of sales and how to negotiate.
Or even James Keyes, the CEO of
not one, but two multi-billion dollar companies, Blockbuster
and 7-Eleven.
He taught our community leadership, team building, and
how to find the right people to help grow
your business.
Guys, if there's anything that I've learned over
the last three years in building a multi-billion
dollar network, interviewing over a thousand
millionaires and over 10 billionaires, it's
that there's only one shortcut to success in today's world.
And that's mentoring.
Mentorship.
And that's why we created
this community in the first place.
And since it's Black Friday this week, we have
an insane deal for you guys to get into
this community for only $30 a month.
The lowest the price has ever
been, the lowest it ever will be.
You have the ability to join this community,
the school of mentors and get directly mentored
by the millionaires and the billionaires
that I interview on this channel.
You get access to my network, the people
you see time and time again that I interview,
you will have the ability to
get that knowledge because guys, information changes.
Any situation.
Remember that information can change situations.
To join this community, go to the
link down in the description of this video.
I cannot wait to see every one
of you guys inside of this community.
With that being said, let's get back to the interview.
Now, throughout your career in terms of
revenue, what was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
250 million.
And what took that company from eight to nine figures?
Yeah, I'll never forget when I was doing
around 10 million a year, I called Tom.
I said, Tom, I don't think I'm a good CEO.
I have no clue what I'm doing.
I'm a sales guy.
I best the sales leader.
And I'm good with money.
Like I'm not a spender.
I didn't buy my first Rolex
till I was 35 years old.
I didn't buy my first Ferragamo shoe till I
was had a half a million in the bank.
I didn't buy a house
until I was 37 years old.
So I'm not the one that's spending all the money.
I'm reinvesting into the company.
I said, but I don't think I'm an operator.
He says, Pat, we need to find a way for
you to go be around other CEOs that have ran bigger
companies.
You'll learn from him.
I went three weeks to Boston.
I went to this Harvard OPM program,
owner, president management program, 144 CEOs, 64
countries.
The man who was my partner sitting
next to me was the founder of the
clothes that girls wear.
What is that company called?
That lingerie that, what is the company?
Victoria's.
He was the Victoria's Secret of New Zealand and Australia.
So I said, how big is your business?
He said, well, you can Google me.
I Googled a guy net worth
one and a half billion dollars.
For three weeks, I kept asking him,
what is my job as a CEO?
He says, I have 7,000 employees
and six CEOs that report to me.
He was the chairman of the board.
And he told me, this is the four things, okay?
You're either one, thinking about linear
growth, which is biz dev and systems.
You can spend money into your systems or biz dev.
Okay.
Networking, shaking hands, but it's
not going to explode your business.
He said, exponential growth is at the top.
Leadership development or innovative campaigns.
For example, like Coke came up
with share a Coke with John.
I'm not a Coke drinker, but I'm
buying the Coke to share it with John.
One great innovative campaign for us when I
came back to our business to the next level.
As a multiple nine figure entrepreneur, what was
the best financial advice that you ever received?
This is not going to be
popular to a lot of people.
Always have cash.
I remember one time I got a call.
A guy says he needs $540,000.
He had two Wayne Gretzky cards.
I said, what kind of cards?
He said,
these are the main cards of
Wayne Gretzky, PSA 10 OPG and Tops.
I said, I'll give you 540, but I
want to pick up the cards in 24 hours.
I'm going to send somebody.
I need you to meet me
at PSA's headquarters in Orange County.
Tikrun who happens to be here.
He flies out to LA.
Yeah, you flew out.
You go meet him.
Pick up, picks up the cards, puts
it in a new case, brings it back.
He's in the airport with a
half a million dollars in his pocket.
That card we sold a year and a half later
was a Guinness Book of World Record for $2.2 million.
This property we're on right now.
The guy that owned this bought it for $25 million.
In 2018, put $7 million of finishes in this.
This was announced that's going on
the public market for an auction.
4,400 people were interested in this property.
131 signed an NDA.
And then there is the day that everybody's bidding.
You have to put a million dollars to compete.
If you don't, you're not competing.
The day the auction comes, everyone's sitting
there and Zoom, 40, 50 people raising hands,
doing the whole thing.
We ended up buying this for $25.2 million cash.
We wired the money a week later.
We bought the property.
This is probably a $40, $50 million property.
Having cash allows you to pick things up.
When they're for sale, unfortunately not having
cash when the market kind of goes bad,
a lot of people don't make it.
I went to a mastermind in March, 2023,
and there was a saying that great businessmen
a lot of time are terrible content
creators and great content creators are terrible businessmen.
What's been your secret to creating wealth in media?
Well, that's the concept with trifecta.
The market's going to tell you if
you know what you're doing or not.
Like right now, I was telling you
earlier, billions of YouTube got you proven
that you know what you're doing.
Now operating different story, right?
The operating aspect is day to day.
Content creation, it's brutal.
You're either able to get the
attention of people or you can't.
I'll never forget this.
Beginning stages of the business.
Mario comes up and he takes out an
iPhone and says, let's start a YouTube channel.
At the time I was only creating
content for my insurance agents that was unlisted.
Wasn't public.
It's private unlisted.
We started.
I said, let's see if the
market likes the way I communicate.
Two years later, we're blown out.
We have around a thousand subscribers.
Nobody watches our content, including my family.
Then we adjust.
I went to an event and at
the event, they said, pick one word.
The one word for me became business and entrepreneurship.
The next five years.
The content we created most of the videos at
the end of it, it had one title in it.
Raising money as an entrepreneur, hiring people
as an entrepreneur, firing people as an entrepreneur.
Two years later, 50% of videos
on page one were from our channel.
And then that's how I started growing.
But the market's going to tell you, you can
either speak, you can either a good for video
or you're good at writing.
Everybody has one of those three
abilities to get their message out.
Now I know in a podcast, that's
how you mentioned that there's four categories.
Everybody needs to be reading about
human nature, sales, negotiation, and money.
What has been your secret to sales?
Your career needs analysis with everybody.
It doesn't matter when my kids,
I have four kids every day.
I do needs analysis with what's a needs analysis.
I like baseball.
I want my son to be a professional baseball player.
I'm a Yankee scout.
So I want him to go
want to be a baseball player.
He could care less about baseball.
He loves watching baseball.
Doesn't like playing baseball.
I do a needs analysis.
Love soccer.
We put him in soccer.
Now he's excelling.
I talked to my oldest son could care less
about sports, but he likes kickboxing and he loves
politics.
So I take him when the Trump interview
came in, he came and met president Trump.
I take him to certain
places because he's interested in politics.
Clients.
Needs analysis.
I'm asking you what's important to you may
be different than what's important to me in
the sales business.
Very few salespeople master art of needs analysis.
The more I do a needs analysis with
you asking you the question that's important to you.
Then I can make the recommendation
based on what's important to you.
Instead of just jumping to conclusion, thinking whatever
I sold to him, I can sell to you.
The art of needs analysis.
You're going to send a rain, by the way.
How awesome is this?
You exited a company for nine figures.
You've been at the table with some hitters.
What is your best negotiation
advice for anybody in business?
Not putting yourself.
In a position where you are desperate.
Whenever you are in a position of desperation,
you're always going to get underpaid and you'll
make a bad move that could
cost you a hundred million dollars.
I'll tell you what happened with me.
First time guy came to
want to buy our company comes.
He's walking around our facility.
He says, do you mind if
I talk to all your employees?
I said, go talk to everybody you want.
You were there.
He goes and talks to everybody.
Then we're going to dinner that night
at this restaurant called Chamberlain's in Dallas.
We sit down.
It's me, his CFO boom.
They have the money to buy the business.
We follow up.
They make the offer.
Here's the offer.
The offer was a small offer.
120 million.
Okay.
He said, however,
the reason why we're making this upper more only giving
you 50% upfront is we need you to stay with
us for five years.
I said, why is that?
He says, when I walked around your facility and
talk to everybody, I asked him how hard does he
work?
And they all said, you are the hardest working
person in the company or they're seven days a
week.
We can't buy the business because you're running a company.
He said, I can't sell it to you.
So I had a new strategy.
I left Texas.
I moved to Florida four years ago.
I hired five new C-suite executives.
They ran the business.
The next time around when they came and
interviewed everybody, they said, Pat's only here once
every six months.
And I'm running by Tim and of our consulting.
From here.
Then I got more than two, two times the
valuation I got just because we were patient, not this
for the way to two years.
When it comes to the way that
people look at money, what separates middle-class from
people who were able to build that
long-term generational wealth, like yourself in today's
world, what's your feeding yourself
and what you're thinking about money.
I mean, at some point in your life, my
dad and I were having a conversation about life
and marriage, and he's telling me
certain fears that he has about marriage.
And I said, dad, timeout.
I don't want to hear that.
He says, why?
I said, I don't want to believe that's the truth.
You may believe that.
I don't want to believe that's the truth.
My mother bought money.
I'm not buying that.
So you have to have one.
At some point in your life, refuse to
buy into the philosophies that your parents and
loved ones sell to you.
If it doesn't make sense, question it.
Don't believe it.
Your last message to somebody out there,
they want to become Patrick, but David wealthy
in today's world.
They want to become really successful.
Your last message.
A guy sends me a minute and he says,
say, Pat, where I'm living at right now, nobody
believes in money.
No entrepreneurs in my country,
no money, much family made money.
None of all this stuff.
He's just saying how it doesn't exist.
So on.
I said, listen, when I was
coming up, there was no you.
You.
There was nobody who follow and seek inspirational content.
Nobody in the world has an experience today.
Learn and went out the heights level.
If you're living in a place
that you don't have access, different story.
But everybody today has access to information
to be able to change their life.
You will not find to the mindset that
it's too hard to get your parents were divorced.
If you grew up in a poor
family, don't buy into any of that stuff.
Anytime.
Hey, you guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
I need you guys to like and subscribe
for amazing content coming every week with the
biggest.
Business moguls in the entire world.
And like I said earlier, guys, you guys
need to join my private community on school, the
school of mentors, where every week you will
get direct mentorship and access to ask questions
to the millionaires and the billionaires
that I interview on this channel.
You do not want to miss out
on this once in a lifetime opportunity.
Guys are black Friday sales live $30 a
month to join, to get access to exclusive masterclasses
and being able to talk to and
ask questions every week to multimillionaires, eight figure
entrepreneurs, nine figure billion dollar.
Company founders and entrepreneurs.
I cannot wait to see you
guys on the inside of the community.
All you need to do is click the link that's
up here right now, or go to the link down in
the description of this video.
With that being said, I can't wait to see
you on the inside of the community and I'll
see you in the next video.
Speaker 1